var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) those",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلَّهِ",
        "answer": "(be) to Allah",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "lillahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " الْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَمْدُ",
        "answer": "All praises and thanks",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 352,
        "tlit": "al-ḥamdu",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " الْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح م د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمْد",
        "waznEnglish": "they be praised",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 43,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of the) Judgment",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": 101,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَالِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 92,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "the Lord",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " الْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "answer": "the Most Gracious",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥmāni",
        "frequency": 339,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحْمَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥmān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحْمَٰنِ",
        "answer": "The Most Gracious",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "al-raḥmāni",
        "frequency": 339,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحْمَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥmān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Most Merciful",
        "pcklId": "216",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥīmi",
        "frequency": 339,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 116,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحِيمِ",
        "answer": "the Most Merciful",
        "pcklId": "217",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥīmi",
        "frequency": 339,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 116,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِسْمِ",
        "answer": "In (the) name",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "bis'mi",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الرَّحْمَٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 39,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الصِّرَاطَ",
        "answer": "(to) the path",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 836,
        "tlit": "l-ṣirāṭa",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " اهْدِنَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ر ط",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) the path",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād rā ṭā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صِرَاطَ",
        "answer": "(The) path",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 836,
        "tlit": "ṣirāṭa",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ر ط",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) the path",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād rā ṭā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الضَّالِّينَ",
        "answer": "(of) those who go astray",
        "pcklId": "173",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "l-ḍālīna",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَعْبُدُ",
        "answer": "we worship",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "naʿbudu",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 122,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "of the universe",
        "pcklId": "476",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " الْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَسْتَعِينُ",
        "answer": "we ask for help",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1041,
        "tlit": "nastaʿīnu",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ع و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَعِينُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seek help",
        "waznTlit": "is'taʿīnu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَغْضُوبِ",
        "answer": "those who earned (Your) wrath",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1067,
        "tlit": "l-maghḍūbi",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "غ ض ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَغْضُوب",
        "waznEnglish": "and will fall the wrath",
        "waznTlit": "maghḍūb",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "غَيْرِ",
        "answer": "not (of)",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "ghayri",
        "frequency": 154,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ الْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا الضَّالِّينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "ghayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "answer": "the straight",
        "pcklId": "646",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "l-mus'taqīma",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " اهْدِنَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَقِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqīm",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X) (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالِكِ",
        "answer": "(The) Master",
        "pcklId": "202",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "māliki",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " مَالِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَٰلِك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "mālik",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْعَمْتَ",
        "answer": "You have bestowed (Your) Favors",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "anʿamta",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " صِرَاطَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنْعَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bestow favor",
        "waznTlit": "anʿama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اهْدِنَا",
        "answer": "Guide us",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "ih'dinā",
        "frequency": 316,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " اهْدِنَا الصِّرَاطَ الْمُسْتَقِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 144,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "(of the) Day",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 1,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَالِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    }
]; 
export default words;